Guide to the Witold Gombrowicz Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Theater Programs, 1964-98; Series IV; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  - IWONA, KSIEZNICZKA BURGUNDA
    - French
      - Maison Populaire de Montreuil, Yvonne, Princesse de Bourgogne, [Chantal Trichet], n.d. (Box 30, Folder 854)
      - Unidentified theater, Yvonne, Princesse de Bourgogne [Laurent Makles], n.d. (Box 30, Folder 855)
    - German
      - Städtische Bühnen Dortmund, Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Walter Czaschke], 1964-65 (Box 30, Folder 856)
      - Wuppertaler Bühnen, Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Peter Löscher], 1968-69 (Box 30, Folder 857)
      - Schiller-Theater (Berlin, Germany), Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Ernst Schröder] (photocopy of program of 1970) (Box 30, Folder 858)
      - [Staatstheater Wiesbaden], Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 859)
      - Unidentified theater company, Yvonne - Prinzessin von Burgund, [Jan Biczycki (photocopy of program [of 1970?]) (Box 30, Folder 860)
      - Städtische Bühnen Frankfurt am Main, Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Wolfram Mehring], 1971 (Box 30, Folder 861)
      - Theater Bremen, Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Wilfried Minks] (photocopy), 1971 (Box 30, Folder 862)
      - Städtische Bühnen Münster, Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Jens Scholkmann], 1973 (Box 30, Folder 863)
      - Schlosstheater Celle, Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Peter Schreiber], (photocopy), 1975 (Box 30, Folder 864)
      - Landestheater Linz, Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Hermann Molzer], 1976 (Box 30, Folder 865)
      - Bayerisches Staatsschauspiel, Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Ingmar Bergman], 1980 (Box 30, Folder 866)
      - Schauspiel Köln, Yvonne, die Burgunderprinzessin, [Luc Bondy], 1980 (Box 30, Folder 867)
      - Basler Theater (Switzerland), Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Peter Lotschak] (photocopy, 2 copies), 1981 (Box 30, Folder 868)
      - Komödianten [?], Yvonne, die BurgunderPrinzessin, [Conny Hannes Meyer] (original and photocopy), 1981 (Box 30, Folder 869)
      - Württembergisches Staatstheater Stuttgart, Yvonne, die Burgunderprinzessin, [Günther Krämer], 1981 (Box 30, Folder 870)
      - Elisabethbühne, Yvonne die Burgunderprinzessin, [Renate Rustler], 1987 (Box 30, Folder 871)
      - Theater der Stadt Schweinfurt, Yvonne, die Burgunderprinzessin, [Henryk Tomaszewski], 1989 (Box 30, Folder 872)
      - Schamburg. Theater der Jugend, Yvonne, die Burgunderprinzessin, [Martin Rengel], 1990 (Box 30, Folder 873)
      - Nationaltheater Mannheim, Yvonne, die Burgunderprinzessin, [Stephan Müller], 1991 (Box 30, Folder 874)
      - Theater der Stadt Heidelberg, Yvonne, die Burgunderprinzessin, [Hans-Ulrich Becker], 1991-92 (Box 30, Folder 875)
      - Theater am Neumarkt (Zürich, Switzerland,) Yvonne, Prinzessin von Burgund, [Jorge Lavelli] (Box 30, Folder 876)
    - Hebrew
      - Cameri Theatre of Tel-Aviv, [Joseph Millo], 1970 (Box 30, Folder 877)
    - Hungarian
      - Petofi Shínház, Yvonne, Burgund Hercegnoje, [Balogh Géza, Krystian Lupa], 1983 (Box 30, Folder 878)
    - Italian
      - Teatro di Porta Romana, Iwona, Principessa di Borgogna, [Massimo Navone], 1982 (Box 30, Folder 879)
        Includes newspaper clippings (photocopies)
      - Teatro della Tosse, Iwona, Principessa di Borgogna, [Tonino Conte], 1990-91 (Box 30, Folder 880)
      - Teatro Libero, Iwona, Principessa di Borgogna, [Armando Pugliese] (Box 30, Folder 881)
    - Japanese
      - Unidentified theater, Tokyo, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 882)
    - Polish
      - Teatr Dramatyczny m. st. Warszawy, Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Gustaw Holoubek], 1975 (Box 31, Folder 883)
      - Teatr im. Jana Kochanowskiego w Opolu, Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Jerzy Golinski], 1976 (Box 31, Folder 884)
      - Teatr im. Wilama Horzycy w Toruniu, Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Krystyna Meissner], 1977 (Box 31, Folder 885)
      - Teatr Polski we Wroclawiu, [Witold Zatorski], Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, (2 copies), 1978 (Box 31, Folder 886)
      - Teatr 77, Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Piotr Krukowski], 1982 (Box 31, Folder 887)
      - Teatr Powszechny w Lodzi, Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Maciej Z. Bordowicz], 1983 (Box 31, Folder 888)
      - Teatr Polski w Szczecinie, Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Marcel Kochanczyk], 1989 (Box 31, Folder 889)
      - Teatr Dramatyczny w Elblagu, Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Jerzy Sopocko], 1990 (Box 31, Folder 890)
      - Teatr im. Wojciecha Boguslawskiego w Kaliszu, Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Anna Augustynowicz] (3 copies), 1991 (Box 31, Folder 891)
      - Ateneum (Warsaw, Poland), Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Waldemar Smigasiewicz, Maciej Wojtyszko], 1994 (Box 31, Folder 892)
      - Teatr Wspólczesny w Szczecinie, Iwona, ksiezniczka Burgunda, [Anna Augustynowicz], 1996 (Box 31, Folder 893)
    - Portuguese
      - Teatro Experimental de Cascais, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 894)
      - Ivone princesa de Borgonha
    - Serbian
      - Beogradsko dramsko pozoriste, Ivona, Burgundska kneginja, [Paolo Madeli], 1985 (Box 31, Folder 895)
    - Slovak
      - Divadlo Andreja Bagara Nitra, Ivona, princezná burgundská, [Emil Horváth], 1993 (Box 31, Folder 896)
    - Spanish
      - Teatro Municipal General San Martín, Yvonne, Princesa de Borgoña, [Jorge Lavelli], 1972 (Box 31, Folder 897)
      - Seminario Teatral de Villa Ballester, El Banquete, [Ruben Fraga], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 898)
    - Swedish
      - Dramatiska Teatern (Stockholm, Sweden), Yvonne, prinsessa av Burgonne, [Alf Sjöberg], (2 copies), 1966 (Box 31, Folder 899)
      - Göteborgs Stadsteater, Yvonne, prinsessa av Burgund, [Gunilla Berg], 1993 (Box 31, Folder 900)
      - Älvsborgs teatern, Yvonne, prinsessa av Burgund, [Frederik Nilson], 1994 (Box 31, Folder 901)
      - Dramatiska Teatern, Yvonne, prinsessa av Burgund, (Stockholm, Sweden), [Mira Teeman], 1995 (Box 31, Folder 902)
      - Unidentified theater company, Yvonne, [Ingmar Bergman], 1995 (Box 31, Folder 903)
      - Ungariks Riksteatern, Yvonne - prinsessa av Burgund, [Elisabeth G. Söderström] (Box 31, Folder 904)
    - Turkish
      - Ankara Devlet Tiyatrosu, Ivona Burgonya prensesi [Ewa Bulhak], 1989 (Box 31, Folder 905)
  - KOSMOS
    - French
      - La Moineau Pendu, [Jacques Mérienne, Nicolas Delétoille] (Box 31, Folder 906)
        Contains an invitation to the lecture
    - Polish
      - Teatr Powszechny im. Jana Kochanowskiego w Radomiu, Kosmos [Waldemar Smigasiewicz] (2 copies), 1995 (Box 31, Folder 907)
  - OPERETKA
    - Bosnian
      - Narodno Pozoriste Sarajevo, Opereta, [Vlado Jablan], 1970 (Box 31, Folder 908)
    - Czech
      - Státní Divadlo v Ostrave, Opereta, [Mojmír Weinmann], 1987 (Box 31, Folder 909)
    - English
      - University of Rochester, Operetta, [Stefan Rudnicki], 1973 (Box 31, Folder 910)
        Includes newspaper clippings, whole issue of Logos (Vol 1, nr 5) and performance review by Paul Hernadi (typescript, annotated, photocopy)
      - Post Summer Theater, Operetta [Stefan Rudnicki], 1983 (Box 31, Folder 911)
        Includes a letter to RG and newspaper clippings
    - Finnish
      - Suomen Kansallistteatteri, ( Operetti, 1970-71 (Box 31, Folder 912)
    - French
      - Théâtre National de la Colline, Opérette [Jorge Lavelli], (2 copies), 1989 (Box 31, Folder 913)
    - German
      - Basler Theater, [Hans Hollman], 1970-71 (Box 31, Folder 914)
      - Schiller-Theater, Operette, (Berlin, Germany), [Ernst Schröder], 1972 (Box 31, Folder 915)
      - Das Junge Theater, Operette, [Oscar Fritz Schuh], (photocopy of program from 1972-73), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 916)
      - Schauspielhaus (Berlin, Germany), Operette, [Fritz Zecha], (photocopy of program of 1972-73), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 917)
      - Kammerspiele (München, Germany), Operette, [Bohumil Herlishka], (photocopy of program from 1973), n.d. (Box 31, Folder 918)
      - [Unidentified theater company], Operette, [Friedrich Beyer and Frank Günther], [1974]
      - [Unidentified theater company], Operette, [Kazimierz Dejmek], (photocopy of program from 1976-77), n.d. (Box 32, Folder 919)
      - Stadttheater St. Gallen, Operette, [Dietmar Pflegerl], (photocopy of program of 1979), n.d. (Box 32, Folder 920)
      - Landestheater Linz, Operette, [Erwin Bigus], (photocopy of program from 1982) (Box 32, Folder 921)
      - Transformtheater Berlin, Operette, [Henryk Baranowski], 1987 (Box 32, Folder 922)
        Includes an invitation card
      - Lanestheater Württemberg-Hohenzollern, Operette, [Gerhard Hess, Wolfram Frank], (2 copies), 1988 (Box 32, Folder 923)
      - Zwischenspieltheater, Operette, [A. Hettmann] (photocopy), n.d. (Box 32, Folder 924)
    - Greek
      - Teatro Technis-Karolos Koun, Operetta, [1972] (Box 32, Folder 925)
    - Hungarian
      - Sziínház Debrecen, Operett, [Eörsi István, Három Részben], [1995-96] (Box 32, Folder 926)
      - R.S.9. Studiotheatre, Operetka [Dezso Dobay and Katalin Laban] (Box 32, Folder 927)
    - Italian
      - Teatro Valle, Operetta, [Antonio Calenda], [1980] (Box 32, Folder 928)
        Includes a newspaper clipping
      - Teatro Stabile dell'Aquila, Operetta, [Antonio Calenda], [1969] (Box 32, Folder 929)
    - Polish
      - Teatr Nowy w Lodzi, Operetka, [Kazimierz Dejmek], 1975 (Box 32, Folder 930)
        Includes invitation for RG, duplicates, newspaper clippings
      - Teatr Polski w Poznaniu, Operetka, [Józef Gruda], 1976-77 (Box 32, Folder 931)
      - Panstwowy Teatr im. Juliusza Osterwy w Lublinie, Operetka, [Zbigniew Sztejman], 1978-79 (Box 32, Folder 932)
        Contains duplicates
      - Teatr Wspólczesny w Szczecinie, Operetka, [Ryszard Major], 1982 (Box 32, Folder 933)
      - Teatr Slaski im. Stanislawa Wyspianskiego w Katowicach, Operetka, [Jerzy Zegalski], 1983 (Box 32, Folder 934)
      - Stary Teatr (Kraków, Poland), Operetka, [Tadeusz Bradecki], 1995 (Box 32, Folder 935)
      - Teatr Wspolczesny we Wroclawiu, Operetka, [Kazimierz Braun], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 936)
    - Swedish
      - Replica, Operett, [Jurek Sawka], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 937)
    - Ukrainian
      - Kharkivskii Derzhavvnii Akademichnii Ukrainskii Dramatichnii Teatr im. T. G. Shevchenka, Opereta, [Gzhegozh Mruvchinskii], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 938)
  - OPETANI
    - Polish
      - Teatr Polski we Wroclawiu, Opetani, [Tadeusz Minc, Elzbieta Morawiec], (2 copies), 1980 (Box 32, Folder 939)
      - Teatr Narodowy (Warsaw, Poland), Opetani [Tadeusz Minc, Elzbieta Morawiec], 1982 (Box 32, Folder 940)
  - "PAMIETNIK STEFANA CZARNIECKIEGO"
    - Polish
      See: Festivals, I Miedzynarodowy
      - Festiwal Gombrowiczowski (1st International Gombrowicz Festival), box 34, folder 999
  - PORNOGRAFIA
    - Polish
      - Teatr Nowy w Lodzi, Pornografia, [Waldemar Zyszkiewicz, Andrzej Maj], 1985 (Box 32, Folder 941)
      - Teatr Dramatyczny im. Jerzego Szaniawskiego w Plocku, Pornografia [Andrzej Pawlowski, Grzegorz Sobocinski], 1989 (Box 32, Folder 942)
  - SLUB
    - Czech
      - [Unidentified theater company], Svatba, [Katarzyna Wrzosek], 1991 (Box 32, Folder 943)
    - Dutch
      - Nieuw Rotterdams Toneel, Het Huwelijk, [Robert de Vries], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 944)
    - French
      - Théâtre Récamier, Le Mariage, [Jorge Lavelli] (photocopy), 1964 (Box 32, Folder 945)
      - Théâtre National de Chaillot, Mariage, [Daniel Martin], 1984 (Box 32, Folder 946)
        Includes leaflets (3 copies)
      - Théâtres de l'autre Europe, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 947)
        Includes performance of Teatr Stary w Krakowie, Slub, [Jerzy Jarocki]
      - Théâtre Acte 3, Mariage, [Jean-Maurice Gélinas], 1994 (Box 32, Folder 948)
        Includes leaflets
      - Théâtre Universitaire de Toulouse le Mirail, Mariage, [Philipe Dupeyron] (leaflets), 1994 (Box 32, Folder 949)
    - German
      - Schiller-Theater, Die Trauung ,(Berlin, Germany), [Ernst Schröder], 1967-68 (Box 32, Folder 950)
      - Nationaltheater Mannheim, Die Trauung, [Ernst Dienst], 1969 (Box 32, Folder 951)
      - Hessisches Staatstheater Wiesbaden, Die Trauung, [Günther Büch], (fragment of program from 1972-73, photocopy) (Box 32, Folder 952)
      - Schauspielhaus Zürich, Die Trauung [Jerzy Jarocki], 1972-73 (Box 32, Folder 953)
      - Bühnen der Stadt Essen, Die Trauung (photocopy of program from 1973-74) (Box 32, Folder 954)
      - Württembergischer Staatstheater [?], Die Trauung, (photocopy of program from 1974), n.d. (Box 32, Folder 955)
      - Hochschule der Künste Berlin, Die Trauung [Jerzy Jarocki], (2 copies), 1990 (Box 32, Folder 956)
      - Staatsspiel Dresden, Die Trauung, [Arne Retzlaff], 1990 (Box 32, Folder 957)
      - Elisabethbühne, Salzburg, Die Trauung [Renate Rustler-Ourth], 1991 (Box 32, Folder 958)
        Includes staging calendar and bank check
      - Theater Scena Polska Hamburg, Die Trauung [Alexander Berlin] (Box 32, Folder 959)
    - Hungarian
      - Kaposvári Csiky Gergely Színház, Esküvo, [Spiró György], n.d. (Box 33, Folder 960)
    - Italian
      - "Porcospino II" (in Palazzo Durini), Il Matrimonio, [Mario Missiroli]), 2 copies, [1968-69] (Box 33, Folder 961)
    - Polish
      - Teatr Dramatyczny m. st. Warszawy, [Gustav Holoubek] (2 copies), 1974 (Box 33, Folder 962)
      - Teatr im. Juliusza Slowackiego w Krakowie, [Krystyna Skuszanka] (2 copies), 1975 (Box 33, Folder 963)
      - Teatr Polski w Szczecinie, Slub, [Krystyna Tyszarska], 1976 (Box 33, Folder 964)
      - Teatr Polski we Wroclawiu, Slub, [Jerzy Grzegorzewski] (3 copies), 1976 (Box 33, Folder 965-966)
        Includes leaflets (4 copies) and program of season 1975/76.
      - Teatr im. Stefana Jaracza w Lodzi, Slub, [Bogdan Hussakowski], 1990 (Box 33, Folder 967)
        See also: Théâtre Espace Acteur, "Un mois de la Pologne à Paris", box 34, folder 994
      - Teatr Polski w Warszawie, Slub, [Tadeusz Minc] (leaflet), 1991 (Box 33, Folder 968)
      - Stary Teatr w Krakowie, Slub, [Jerzy Jarocki] (2 copies), 1991 (Box 33, Folder 969)
        Includes leaflet
    - Russian
      - Russkii dramaticheskii teatr Litvy, Brak, [Jacek Zembrzuski] (2 copies), 1994 (Box 33, Folder 970)
      - Teatr im. Stefana Jaracza w Lodzi, Venchanie, [Bogdan Hussakowski], (multiple copies), 1991 (Box 33, Folder 971)
    - Serbian
      - Unidentified theater, Venchan'e, [Jerzy Jarocki], 1981 (Box 33, Folder 972)
    - Spanish
      - Teatro Municipal General San Martin, El Casamiento, [Laura Yusem], 1981 (Box 33, Folder 973)
    - Swedish
      - Dramatiska Teatern (Stockholm, Sweden) Vigseln, [Alf Sjöberg], 1966 (Box 33, Folder 974)
      - Unidentified theater company, Vigseln, [Ulf Fredrikssen], 1969 (Box 33, Folder 975)
      - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden), Vigseln, [Karl Dunér] (2 copies), 1995 (Box 33, Folder 976)
  - "TANCERZ MECENASA KRAJKOWSKIEGO"
    - French
      - Unidentified theater company, Le Danseur de Maître Kraykowski, [Jörg Schnass], (3 copies), n.d. (Box 33, Folder 977)
        Includes press release
    - Polish
      - Teatr w Radomiu, Tancerz Mecenasa Kraykowskiego, [Krzysztof Warlikowski], 1997 (Box 33, Folder 978)
  - TRANS-ATLANTYK
    - Polish
      - Teatr im. Stefana Jaracza w Lodzi, Trans-Atlantyk, [Mikolaj Grabowski] (2 copies), 1981 (Box 33, Folder 979)
      - Teatr Polski we Wroclawiu, Trans-Atlantyk, [Eugeniusz Korin], (2 copies), 1982 (Box 33, Folder 980)
      - Teatr Slaski im. Stanislawa Wyspianskiego w Katowicach, Trans-Atlantyk, [Mikolaj Grabowski, Ewa Kutrys] (2 copies), 1993 (Box 33, Folder 981)
  - "ZBRODNIA Z PREMEDYTACJA"
    - Polish
      - Teatr im. Stefana Jaracza w Lodzi, Zbrodnia z premedytacja, [Zbigniew Brzoza], 1996 (Box 33, Folder 982)
  - "ZDARZENIA NA BRYGU BRANBURY"
    - French
      - Théâtre de Chambre, Événements sur la goélette 'Banbury', n.d. (Box 33, Folder 983)
  - OTHER PRODUCTIONS
    - French
      - [Actuel Acteurs Free Théâtre?], Classes Gombrowicz, [Claude Bernhardt, Jacques Mérienne], 1989 (Box 33, Folder 984)
      - Unidentified theater company, La lycéenne et Gombrowicz, [Catherine Espinasse], 1979 (Box 33, Folder 985)
        Includes newspaper clippings (photocopies) and a poster
      - Université de Paris VIII: Vincennes, C.ie Transthéâtrale [Franck Lepage, Jean-Marc Montel, Alberto Hernandez, Jean-Jacques Mazur, Christine Jurion, Raoul Fernandez, Safaa Fathy], 1985 (Box 33, Folder 986)
      - France 3 cinéma, Océaniques, Moi, Gombrowicz, [Andrzej Wolski], 1989 (Box 33, Folder 987)
      - Actuel Acteurs Free Théâtre, W comme Gombrowicz, [Jean Gillibert, Jacques Mérienne], 1992 (Box 33, Folder 988)
    - Polish
      - Teatr Nowy w Lodzi, Ja, Gombrowicz, [Wojciech Szulczynski], 1988 (Box 33, Folder 989)
      - Teatr Nowy w Warszawie, Czaber z Gombra, [Adam Hanuszkiewicz], 1992 (Box 33, Folder 990)
  - FESTIVALS
    - XVI Festiwal Polskich Sztuk Wspólczesnych (Wroclaw, Poland), 1975 (Box 34, Folder 991)
    - 24 Festiwal Polskich Sztuk Wspólczesnych (Wroclaw, Poland), 1985 (Box 34, Folder 992)
      Includes a letter to RG from Maria Debicz
    - Eenakterfestival [Netherlanden], 1986 (Box 34, Folder 993)
    - Théâtre Espace Acteur, "Un mois de la Pologne à Paris", 1990 (Box 34, Folder 994)
      Includes newspaper clippings
    - Emergences. Festival des nouvelles tendances théâtrales, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 995)
    - 31 Kaliskie spotkania teatralne, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 996)
      Includes letters to RG
    - I Miedzynarodowy Festiwal Gombrowiczowski w Radomiu (1st International Gombrowicz Festival in Radom)
      - Program (3 copies), 1993 (Box 34, Folder 997)
      - Material related to the festival, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 998)
      - Includes calendars, interview questions, RG's custom documents, cards, an official letter to Wojciech Kepczynski (photocopy).
      - Pamietnik Stefana Czarnieckiego, [Jerzy Stepkowski] (program), 1993 (Box 34, Folder 999)
    - II Miedzynarodowy Festiwal Gombrowiczowski w Radomiu (2nd International Gombrowicz Festival in Radom)
      - Program (2 copies), 1995 (Box 34, Folder 1000)
      - Dzienniczek festiwalowy [issues of the festival daily] (multiple copies), 1995 (Box 34, Folder 1001)
      - Invitation for RG, programs and calendars, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 1002)
      - Materials loosely related to the festival (publications about Radom Teatr and the Public Library in Radom, postcards), 1994-95, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1003)
    - III Miedzynarodowy Festiwal Gombrowiczowski w Radomiu (3rd International Gombrowicz Festival in Radom)
      - Program (2 copies), 1997 (Box 34, Folder 1004)
      - Vladimiro Elvieri, Graffiti per Gombrowicz (festival publication), 1997 (Box 34, Folder 1005)
    - Festival Polonais en Ille-et-Vilaine, 1997 (Box 34, Folder 1006)
- Writings by Others About Gombrowicz, 1960-97; Series V; 3.75; (9 boxes)
  Series V is organized into seven subseries: Cahier de l'Herne: Gombrowicz; Published Letters; Bibliography; Articles; Biographical Articles and Notes; Transcripts of Radio Broadcasts; and Theses and Student Essays.
  - CAHIER de L'HERNE: GOMBROWICZ
    Published: Paris, Éditions de L'Herne, [1971], ed. Constantin Jelenski and Dominique de Roux.
    Includes WG's working files and drafts of his articles
    - List of persons who were considered for contributing, typescript with WG's annotations, 1966 Sep 11? (Box 35, Folder 1007)
    - WG's notes, holograph, 1969 Jul (Box 35, Folder 1008)
      Includes note by RG
    - List of persons, notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1009)
    - Table of contents, typescript annotated by third party, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1010)
    - ["Bruno Schulz et Ferdydurke"] draft of a footnote and other notes, holograph (Box 35, Folder 1011)
    - ["Deux polémiques"], drafts and notes, holograph (Box 35, Folder 1012)
    - "G. vu par...," drafts and notes, holograph annotated (Box 35, Folder 1013)
    - "Gombrowicz et les Polonais"
      Article by WG, corrected by Constantin Jelenski after WG's death
      - Working file (newspaper clippings and list of names) (Box 35, Folder 1014)
      - Working file (Maria Paczowska's letter and the text written in her hand), typescript, manuscript (Box 35, Folder 1015)
      - Working file (Letters to Kultura concerning WG), typescript, typescript (photocopy), 1951-67 (Box 35, Folder 1016)
      - Working file (photocopies of letters to WG, dated 1949-68), n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1017-1018)
      - Working file (photocopies of letters to WG, dated 1950-67), n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1019)
        Originals do not occur in the collection
      - Working file (photocopies of Alexandra Orme's letters to WG, dated 1950-56) (Box 35, Folder 1020)
      - Typescript corrected by Constantin Jelenski, (photocopy), n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1021)
    - ["Gombrowicz est parmi nous"] by Pierre Babin, typescript, 1968 Nov 10 (Box 35, Folder 1022)
    - "Le chemin difficile de la facilité" by Carl Gustaf Bjurström, typescript (Box 35, Folder 1023)
    - "L'influence croissante de Gombrowicz," unidentified, typescript, n.d (Box 35, Folder 1024)
    - Synopses and fragments of articles by Lars Gustafsson, Paul Beers and Koos Geenen, transcript, typescript (photocopy), 1967 (Box 35, Folder 1025)
      Includes letter from Lars Gustafsson
    - "Listy niepolskie" ["Non-Polish letters"], working file (photocopies of letters to WG dated 1947-68), n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1026)
    - Dust cover, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1027)
    - Original folders for the Cahier de L'Herne files, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1028)
  - PUBLISHED LETTERS
    - "Witold Gombrowicz. Listy do Adama Mauersbergera," printed version, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 1029)
      Published: Lódz, Lódzkie Towarzystwo Przyjaciol Ksiazki, 1988
    - "Listy Witolda Gombrowicza do Ireny i Bohdana Osadczuków," printed version (photocopy), 1985 (Box 35, Folder 1030)
      Published in: Berlin, Archipelag, 4 (19) 1985
    - "Listy Witolda Gombrowicza do Artura Sandauera," newspaper clippings (photocopy), 1981
      Published in: Kultura, 1981
    - "Bruno Schulz / Witold Gombrowicz. An Exchange of Letters and a Review," translated by Victoria Nelson and Alexander Fiut, printed version (photocopy) (Box 35, Folder 1031)
    - "Listy Witolda Gombrowicza do Józefa Wittlina," printed version, 1985 (Box 35, Folder 1032)
      Published in: Ruch Literacki, 1985 No 1
  - BIBLIOGRAPHY
    - General
      - "Bibliographie des articles publiées sur Gombrowicz," by Joël Jégouzo, computer printout, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1033)
      - "Bibliographie des oeuvres de Witold Gombrowicz publiées depuis 1972" by RG, typescript carbon, annotated, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 1034)
      - "Bibliografia podmiotowa" by Zofia Bilek-Dabrowska, printed version (photocopy), n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1035)
        Fragment of: Gombrowicz i krytycy, Wydawnictwo Literackie, Krakow 1984; Includes the table of contents
      - "Selected Bibliography of Witold Gombrowicz's Works" and "Selected Bibliography on Gombrowicz" by Zofia Bilek-Dabrowska, printed version (photocopy) (Box 35, Folder 1036)
      - Bibliography by Allen Kuharski
        - "Witold Gombrowicz: Selected Bibliography," computer printout, 1997 Sep 3 (Box 35, Folder 1037)
        - "Production History of Gombrowicz's Works," computer printout, 1997 Jul 6 (Box 35, Folder 1038)
        - Working file on theater productions of works by WG, manuscript (photocopy), typescript, typescript (photocopy), computer printout, printed material (photocopy), 1975-77, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1039)
          Includes information collected by RG and annotations by RG
      - Library catalogue cards (photocopy), n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1040)
      - Printout of library catalogues at the University of Montreal, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1041)
        With program of Russian and Slavic studies
    - Bibliography by country of publication
      Arranged alphabetically by the country of interest
      - [Argentina], "Bibliographie Argentine des articles de Gombrowicz," typescript annotated, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1042)